Dimitris Kottas

Web Developer

Email: dkottas1973@gmail.com

Phone: +30 693 200 1313
Website: www.cuboctaedro.eu

Github: https://github.com/Cuboctaedro

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dikottas
Address: Lomvardou 23-25, 11473, Athens, Greece

I am a self-taught developer with 12 years experience in the design and development of websites and web apps. I have experience in managing complex projects, working either solo or inside a team.

I consider myself a Jack of all Trades, always interested in learning new technologies and expanding my skills.

Experience

2019 - Now

Full-stack developer at Nelios

- Various websites and plugins on an existing WordPress multisite environment.
- Developed from scratch SaaS applications using Laravel, NestJs,
 React.
- Websites using Next.js with WordPress backend.

2022 November - December

JavaScript instructor for ANKA

- I have taught a 50 hour course on JavaScript for beginners.

2008 -2019

Freelance Web Developer

- Full-stack development of websites for artists, galleries and small businesses using WordPress, Kirby CMS, Hugo and Eleventy.
- Small e-commerce websites, websites for events and services.
- Designed many of the websites that I developed.

2001 - 2009

Graphic Designer and Editor at Links Books

Before working as a web developer I have worked for many years as a graphic designer and editor in the field of publishing. I have managed and designed complex publications of technical multi-volume books from their initial conception until printing.

Skills

HTML: Semantic, accessible and SEO-friendly HTML

CSS: SASS, Stylus, PostCSS pre-proccessors. Use of BEM, ITCSS, Atomic Design methodologies. CSS Modules, CSS-in-JS, TailwindCSS.

Javascript: Vanilla JS, Typescript, React (SPA, Next, Gatsby), NodeJS (Express, Nest). Extensive experience with jQuery.

PHP: OOP and good knowledge of Laravel. Expert knowledge of WordPress and Kirby CMS. Experience with other php-based cms platforms.

Databases: Extensive use of MySQL and MongoDb.

SSG and Jamstack: Experience with Hugo, Metalsmith and Eleventy static site generators.

APIs: REST and GraphQL client and server. Experience consuming various third party apis.

Design: Functional, responsive and mobile-first designs with attention to detail and typography. Ability to understand and implement existing designs. Knowledge of Figma, extensive experience with Adobe Suite.

Devops: Experience with Netlify and Vercel. Basic experience with AWS.

Other: Basic knowledge of Python, Go and Java.

Examples of work

Ela Meteora Trikala

I was the lead developer for this project. It's a travel guide for the region of Trikala in Thessaly, Greece. The front end is a Next.js app that communicates via GraphQL with a headless WordPress backend. This was the first project in the company to use React. Since then it has been used as a guide for setting up Next.js projects and communicating with the WordPress API.

elameteoratrikala.com

Doryssa

This is a hotel website that is part of a multi-site WordPress with almost 100 websites. This was the first time we added a site that was both multilingual and that presented a group of hotels instead of a single one. This added an extra degree of complexity that was not accounted for in the initial development of the backend.

doryssa.gr

Online check in

This is a saas application for online check in at hotels. Although the front end is just one form, a complex back-end allows each hotel to customize the form and review customer information. The first version was created rapidly at the beginning of the COVID pandemic. Although it was meant as a temporary solution it became popular with clients. In January 2023 we launched the second version, with multi language support and a custom admin interface made with React.

Checkinform.online

Voltes.City

This project was done as a freelance job. It is a website for a company that organizes tours for children and adults in Athens. It was made using Kirby CMS. The public part presents the tours and offers booking services. The admin area is not only for data entry but also as a booking management system created in close collaboration with the company.

Voltes.city

Languages

Greek: native

English: excellent
Spanish: excellent

German: good

Education

2000 - 2001

"Metrópolis", Master program in Architecture and Urban Culture, Universidad Politécnica de Cataluña (UPC), Barcelona

1990 - 1999

NTUA, Faculty of Architecture, Architecture Diploma